[{"topic": "Energy", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "At Company ABC we use a variety of robust internal software programs. Do you consider yourself tech savvy and a fast learner?", "answers": ["Many energy companies will use robust software programs that you may not have even heard of. Because of this, you may not have the exact experience that Company ABC is looking for. Do not fret! All you need to do is display to the interviewer that you have a general understanding of how their technology works. Display that you are tech savvy and a fast learner. If Company ABC has their programs listed in the job posting, be sure to research those programs a bit before your interview.", "\"I am an advanced level user in all of the programs used in my current company.  From your job posting I see that you use X, Y, and Z at Company ABC. I am familiar with how these programs work. I pick up on new technology quickly, and I am willing to get a head start through some helpful online tutorials so that I am a touch more up to speed on my first day with Company ABC.\"", "\"I had taken some courses in computer programming and also worked part-time evenings as an IT support person when I was attending University. I consider myself to be technically inclined. Could you share with me the primary programs you use at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I cannot recall the exact number, but I think it was around three days total. All absences were excused and with notice.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "There are a lot of red tape and regulations in energy related projects.  Are you accustomed to waiting on logistics and policy during your projects?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have the fortitude to outlast any policy restrictions that may hold your projects back. Discuss the ways that you are accustomed to changes in regulations and policy mid-project.", "\"I understand that the energy industry is privy to many policy changes and I am accustomed to setbacks coming my way. I have also experienced setbacks from early-stage funding falling through. Over the years I have gained a lot of patience when it comes to the advancements of my projects and can step away from a project that may be falling behind, look at the situation critically, and reassess my approach when needed.\"", "\"I am no stranger to policy changes. I am well aware that setbacks happen during projects, regardless of the industry. Changes and setbacks can be disheartening at times but it all balances out when I am able to enjoy the success of a well done project.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "How do you handle a situation where your supervisor does not properly communicate information to you?", "answers": ["You cannot force others to communicate with you in a way that you would always prefer. Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have handled a supervisor who does not interact with you in a way that you like.", "\"Whenever I have had a supervisor who does not properly communicate with me, I try to learn their style of communication and emulate it. Sometimes you simply have to relate to others in their style to be understood.\"", "\"I have worked for a previous supervisor who was incredibly brief in his communication. Many times, I would have to put the pieces together for myself. I managed through it, and it taught me independent thought.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Have you ever had to take on a task or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. What was the outcome, and what did you learn?", "\"When my manager went on unexpected medical leave for three months last year I was asked to step into her position in the interim. I knew the basics but was certainly not trained on the specifics of the role. I was able to take it on successfully by leaning on my team, reading a lot of company manuals, and asking many questions. Once my manager returned she was very pleased with the progress that I made, and I was awarded a promotion.\"", "\"I am often asked to perform tasks outside of my wheelhouse. This includes customer dispute resolution and interviewing potential new employees. I am a diverse employee and am happy to take on additional functions.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Do you feel performance should be rewarded over experience?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you should be paid based on tenure, or results? Discuss this with the interviewer and back your answer with an example, if possible.", "\"I feel that employees should be paid, and rewarded, based on their performance. A new employee would be greatly motivated through being rewarded for performance, and it encourages a healthy competition with tenured employees.\"", "\"I feel both performance and experience should be equally rewarded and weighted.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Tell me about your experiences giving presentations in front of large groups.", "answers": ["Public speaking can be intimidating so assure the interviewer that you are capable of communicating well in front of large groups. Have you taken any courses or training in public speaking? Perhaps you have so much experience that it comes second nature. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of giving presentations.", "\"In my past two roles I have been responsible for regularly presenting to my team of 43 staff as well as to our entire warehouse team of over 200. I have taken a couple of Toastmasters sessions which helped a great deal. I am a confident public speaker.\"", "\"Presenting to large groups is a big part of successfully rolling out great communications to teams organization-wide.  I have experience preparing the deck to be presented to ensure it is simple and thorough.  I utilize different communication techniques to make a presentation fun, interesting, and engaging.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Tell me when you have delegated tasks effectively.", "answers": ["Delegating tasks to employees is always a requirement when you are in a management type of role. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to delegate and empower your employees.", "\"I find that to delegate tasks effectively you first need to understand each employee's strengths. I will always delegate to someone's strength so that they will organically know how to complete the task. This method eliminates a lot of resistance and promotes effective and productive work.\"", "\"In my current position, prioritization of our workload is critical to our success. I tap into the resources of my team by finding out their strengths and career aspirations, then assigning them work that will compliment them.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "At Company ABC we put a strong focus on health and safety. What is your experience with health and safety in the energy industry?", "answers": ["Health and safety efforts are incredibly important when it comes to any industry. Show the interviewer that you also emphasize workplace safety. If you have any related training, this is a great time to discuss.", "\"Last year I attended a health and safety course directed at upstream oil and gas. It was an eye-opening experience, and I understand even more so, how important workplace safety is. I appreciate hearing that Company ABC puts such a strong emphasis here.\"", "\"As I am new to the industry, I have not taken many energy industry related health and safety courses. I do have CPR and First Aid training. If you could tell me the type of training that you are looking for in your next hire, I would be happy to get a head start on those courses.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Do people see you as a trustworthy and honest individual?", "answers": ["It is easy to say that you are trustworthy and honest, but it's best if you can back it up with a review or words from a previous supervisor.", "\"I am told quite often that I am an honest and trustworthy individual and you will be able to hear that directly from my supervisor when you call for a reference. I hold honesty and trustworthiness as fundamental virtues.\"", "\"My friends and family rely on me heavily because I am trustworthy and honest.  They can count on me to be straightforward with them and depend on me to be there when it matters least or most.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of emphasis on attention to detail which some people mistake for micromanagement. How do you feel about this?", "answers": ["Many companies will closely control the details of each project. This close control can often be mistaken as micromanagement which not everyone enjoys. Assure the interviewer that you are comfortable working in a role where the details are valued.", "\"I naturally pay close attention to details so to be asked about the finer details of a project is of no concern to me. I am happy to comply with any project checklists.\"", "\"I work very well on an independent basis; however, it is nice to be checked in on every now and then! I don't mind having my work double checked or proofed.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Describe a time when you motivated yourself to complete an assignment or task that you did not feel like doing.", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you will still get the job done even when you aren't excited about the task at hand. Think about a time when there was a work-related task that you did not want to do. Perhaps the dreaded file room needed to be purged of outdated files to make room for new files.  \n\nTell the interviewer what your task was, and explain why you were not excited about it. Be sure to tell the interviewer that even though you were not enthusiastic about the work, you made it happen promptly knowing that it would help the organization as a whole.", "\"I like to set rewards for myself when there are undesirable tasks at hand. For instance, a large part of what I do is review all of the resumes that come into our job portal on a weekly basis. Sometimes there will be up to 200 resumes to review. They all begin to look the same after awhile, so I have set a goal to look at 20 at a time, give myself a quick break, then return to the task.\"", "\"I do not particularly like filling out a CRM. I don't think any salesperson does. It's just not how we are built! We like the call, the chase, the close. Taking time to pause and write out the details of our conversation, projections, and all that jazz is not something we like. It slows us down. However, it's a necessary step in the sales process. Not only does it ultimately help that sale go better when the CRM is filled out in full detail, but also it helps inform the next sales' close rate. It's an important tool in the sale, and even if it takes slowing down and doing a seemingly monotonous task, it's a task that will help me as a salesperson and the organization as a whole.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "In which ways do you feel that Company ABC stands out from industry competitors?", "answers": ["It is essential that you research Company ABC, and the competitive space, before your interview. Discuss with the interviewer how you feel that they stand out from other energy-focused organizations. Keep your answer positive and to the point.", "\"I have researched Company ABC as well as Company ABC and XYZ as I believe those to be the strongest competitors in this industry. One thing that stands out to me is that Company ABC seems to put a stronger and more positive emphasis on environmental concerns. Your involvement with community concerns and innovative technology is also inspiring.\"", "\"Company ABC has been around a lot longer than many competitors, and your name is often mentioned in the news as well as other industry leading publications. I feel this sets you apart in your industry and sets you up as an industry expert and influencer.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals with related post-secondary education. Walk me through your formal education.", "answers": ["Your post-secondary details will likely be on your resume; however, the interviewer would like for you to go into further detail. Discuss your degree, the areas where you excelled, and any awards or recognition you received.", "\"I have a Master's degree in Energy Systems Management from the University of San Francisco. I graduated with honors which is something that I am proud of.\"", "\"My Bachelor's degree is in Business Administration which is not directly related to what you do at Company ABC. With that said, I did learn a lot about organizational development, behavior, and project management. These skills will certainly help me in this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "The energy sector often sees changes in regulation and policy. How do you keep up to date on changes in our industry?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you are genuinely interested in the energy sector by staying up to date on industry news and changes. Perhaps you regularly read a publication that was of great interest. Maybe you follow a certain energy blogger or news channel? Ensure that your answer is enthusiastic and, if you use Company ABC as an information resource, be sure to mention that as well.", "\"To stay up to date on industry changes, I read the Breaking Energy publication on a daily basis. Also, I follow a blog on remediation law. I am very interested in the changes in the energy sector and find the regulatory news section on your website to be very resourceful as well.\"", "\"I have google alerts set up, using keywords related directly to my niche. These help me to stay on top of any industry or regulatory changes, and they save me the time of having to comb through countless publications to keep up. I also follow Company ABC posts on sustainability and environmental concerns, on a regular basis.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "What are your thoughts on the stance environmentalists take against some of our practices in the energy industry?", "answers": ["The energy industry is rarely free of criticism. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on a recent hot topic. You can show the interviewer that you keep up to date on industry news and that you have a well researched, and valuable, opinion.", "\"There are many hot topics when it comes to the energy industry. We are no stranger to controversy which is why I seek to work for a reputable organization such as Company ABC. One recent topic has caught my attention, and that is the oil drilling activity in West Africa. I've been following many environmentalist blogs to get a well-rounded view of the controversy. Everyone is entitled to their opinion, but if I am confident in our ethics, then that's all I need.\"", "\"I respect what environmentalists are attempting to achieve, and I agree with much of it. What I do not agree with is how some of the extremists are portraying our industry. Our industry is vital, and sometimes the extreme environmentalists do not appear to understand that or care to learn.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "The energy sector has many competitors. Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer the ways that Company ABC stands out from their competitors. What caught your eye when applying here? Perhaps it was the information you came across on their website? Maybe you liked how their job posting was worded? Or - perhaps you have a strong referral from a friend or acquaintance. With enthusiasm, discuss why you want to work for Company ABC.", "\"I understand there are many options when seeking a career in the energy industry; however, I am most interested in working for Company ABC because you value continued education and put a strong emphasis on being environmentally responsible.\"", "\"I have been passively seeking a new position for quite some time and haven't jumped on anything yet because I want to make sure it's the right fit. I feel that this job is right for me, at this point in my career, because it offers an opportunity for me to utilize my recent education in GIS while giving me an opportunity to advance in my management skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Do you have any experience in SAP?", "answers": ["Many energy companies will use robust software, including SAP. Because there are endless choices in SAP based programs, you will likely not have the exact experience in the SAP module that Company ABC is looking for. Do not fret! All you need to do is display to the interviewer that you have a general understanding of how their technology works. Display that you are tech savvy and a fast learner. If Company ABC has their programs listed in the job posting, be sure to research those programs a bit before your interview.", "\"I have approximately two years' experience in Fieldglass which is an internal SAP used at Company ABC.  From your job posting I see that you use X, Y, and Z at Company ABC. I am familiar with how these programs work. Technology is very interesting to me, and I am a quick study.\"", "\"I have not been lucky enough to have exposure to SAP as of yet; however, I have watched a few tutorials on the program and am confident in my ability to pick it up very quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["When an interviewer asks an open-ended question like this, it can be difficult to know where to begin...and end! This question haunts many individuals who may accidentally go a little too in-depth into their personal lives. It happens. Keep your reply light, and work relevant. Share how you became interested in this career path and what you enjoy about it. This question is an excellent opportunity to describe yourself by discussing the strengths and qualities that you bring.", "\"I am a competitive individual who is driven and likes to win. In addition to my successful sales career, I also spend time playing competitive sports. I give back by volunteering at the local animal shelter and working for a variety of annual fundraisers in our community.\"", "\"I am a passionate, excited team player who loves to learn on the fly, take the lead when possible, and I have a proven track record of success. I'm loyal and have shown that through my decade-long career at one employer. I have risen through their ranks, and am ready to take on the next challenge. Outside of work, I love to travel and do DIY projects in my home.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "What accomplishment do you believe was the most difficult for you to achieve, in your most recent position?", "answers": ["Being able to face a challenging or stressful situation, and still gain some accomplishment, in the end, is very satisfying. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to come out on top despite being faced with an obstacle.", "\"In my career, so far, I feel that the most difficult accomplishment for me to achieve were the three back-to-back promotions in my current company. Because promotions are granted based on results, I had to put in a lot of overtime hours, and hustle, to get there.\"", "\"My most challenging accomplishment was to boost employee morale, lower turnover and increase productivity.  After the year they had, it was not easy to take over, gain their trust, and put a smile back on their faces.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "What type of work environment do you dislike working in?", "answers": ["Are you pretty flexible in your ability to work in most environments? Have you experienced a position where the atmosphere wasn't conducive to your productivity?  Be sure to know the type of environment that is offered in this position before the interview.", "\"I can be productive in most work environments, so long as the mentality is positive and teamwork is encouraged. I cannot work in an environment that feels negative or toxic. This is not a concern for me with Company ABC as I have read many great employee reviews on Glassdoor and your commitment to your workplace culture is evident.\"", "\"I tend to find slow paced or red tape environments challenging to maintain my excitement levels. With that said, even if I can experience a small win along the way, it is enough to keep me going.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "How do you deal with uncomfortable situations?", "answers": ["Often, our work environment holds the possibility for awkward or tense situations. It can be challenging to know how to respond when you have a coworker who is moody, or when your coworker lacks social skills and continually asks inappropriate questions. The interviewer wants to know that you can keep your cool in situations like these.", "\"I have had my share of awkward situations and having raised two kids, I am no stranger to them! In the workplace, if an uncomfortable situation arises I tend to face the issue head-on, but tactfully. Sweeping things under the rug rarely helps. I have no problem being open with my team or colleagues if I am not feeling comfortable in a particular situation.\"", "\"I have learned over the years that if something makes me uncomfortable, I better dive right in. Change and growth happen outside of your comfort zone. I embrace this!\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"I am motivated by knowing something about the end customer and being able to relate to them as a person. A personal touch is always helpful for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Tell me about a time when you received criticism from your manager. How did you react to that criticism? How did you make improvements based on that criticism?", "answers": ["When you are thinking about examples of criticism, it's best to show that you want to grow as an employee and that you can handle constructive criticism because it helps you learn and improve the quality of your work.", "\"I was instructed to create some presentations for our events. After my manager reviewed my work, some of the slides required an additional copy, and he had different design concepts in mind. He had a background in graphic design, and since I do not, I listened to his ideas and incorporated them. I thought they looked very professional and in the following presentations, I tried to include those design concepts.\"", "\"I was very eager to climb the ranks in my most recent position. My manager, and the VP of Sales, really appreciated this hunger and grit. However, I did receive the feedback that I needed to slow down. As frustrating as it was, I listened. I dedicated my time to learning as much as I could in my current position and paced myself much better post-feedback.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "What do you see as the most difficult task in being a manager?", "answers": ["Being in a management role is always a significant challenge. Share with the interviewer what you feel is the most challenging part of being a manager, and why. Also, discuss what you are currently doing to make this task less complicated in the future.", "\"As a manager, the most difficult task for me is to delegate the work evenly. You will always have team members who are absolute rockstars, then some who are a bit less enthusiastic or are lower producers. I have to remind myself to distribute the work and responsibilities evenly despite my natural inclination to give more work to the high performers. I am currently working with my underperforming team members to prepare them for a larger workload.\"", "\"I would say the most difficult part of managing people is being both their friend and earning their respect while being new on the team. To balance all of these roles, you have to make sure to be approachable and genuinely interested in them as humans, but also make sure they know that it's a place of business and that meeting or exceeding expectations is the name of the game, above all else.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "When faced with a problem, are you more likely to jump into solving it, or are you the type to carefully assess the issue first?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about your problem-solving skills, and your personality. Discuss how you tackle problems when they arise, and keep your answer work-related if you can. Whether you are the type to jump right into solving a problem or you are more methodical in your approach, highlight to the interviewer that you are capable of handling issues professionally while using sound judgment.", "\"When faced with a problem, I am more likely to jump right into solving it. I believe that you cannot leave a problem to fester or become bigger than it already is. You have to take ownership of the issue, and involve yourself in the resolution right away. With that said, I am responsible for my decision making and certainly don't jump in blind. If I am unsure of what action to take, I will ask my leader for advice.\"", "\"I'm a 'roll up my sleeves' kind of person. I see a problem, envision a solution, and begin to tackle it, figuring it out as I go and asking for help along the way.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Looking at your resume, I see multiple gaps between employments, what were you doing during those gaps?", "answers": ["There are many reasons for having a gap in your resume, and it's best, to be honest about the reasons.", "\"I had a gap from 2009-2010 while I was on maternity leave and then another for six months in 2015 while I cared for an ailing parent. During that time I was vigilant in keeping up to date on the market so that my knowledge did not become redundant.\"", "\"Any gaps in my employment are for a good reason. I was laid off during the recession in 2011 and then again in 2016 when my temporary contract came to an end. I am looking for a position now with long-term security.\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Energy", "question": "Why should we hire you to work at Company ABC?", "answers": ["If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what they feel sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived.\n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! This answer could include any industry accolades, extraordinary achievements, additional industry related training, a second language, or how involved you are in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started with my current company, I was the youngest salesperson they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from becoming the #1 sales person in the company within six months. I am dedicated to my craft and engaged in the energy industry to the point where I commit myself to taking at least one business development or leadership related workshop every business quarter. I am a competitive achiever who will show full appreciation for your professional development opportunities. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\"", "\"When I read the job description, I smiled because it was truly as though you had written it with me in mind. I know that I am the best candidate for this role because I consistently exceed goals and I know the energy industry. Also, I was the fastest promoted in my previous position and have led the rollout of new markets in my current position, making me ideally positioned for helping you continue to build your sales organization, markets, and exceed financial metrics. Not to mention, I am looking for a company that I can stay with for the long haul, something that you mentioned you value.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Tell me about a time when you witnessed unsafe behavior in the field. What did you do?", "answers": ["A few years ago, The RAD Group did a significant study related to workplace safety. They found that only 2 in 5 employees felt comfortable reporting unsafe behavior. The observation study also showed that the average employee performs three unsafe acts per week. \n\nThe interviewer would like to know that he/she can trust you to report unsafe work or unsavory behavior in the workplace. The oil and gas industry has incredibly stringent safety regulations and Company ABC must make sure that they are hiring someone who honors their commitment to safety. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about the steps you would take if you witnessed unsafe behavior in the field. If you have personally seen some dangerous behavior, discuss the specifics.", "\"In my previous role I often saw co-workers engaging in dangerous work without taking proper breaks and rests. This overexertion is common in the field because people focus on getting the job done as soon as possible. If I witnessed this unsafe behavior, I would ask my coworker to take a rest and would offer to jump in, or call someone new to the floor to take over.\"", "\"I recently saw a co-worker not wearing their proper PPE. Safety gear is non-negotiable, in my opinion, so I approached them immediately about their choice not to protect themselves properly. According to my company's regulations, I had to write a report on the incident. I trust it will not happen again. I understand these safety rules are in place for everyone's protection so I will do what I can to uphold the regulations.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Tell me about your education and how it relates to the oil, gas, or energy sector.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like for you to take a few minutes to highlight your educational background. You can mention your GPA, your major or minor and also any accolades and awards that you received during your university career. If you were involved in student-led clubs or other extracurriculars, you could mention that as well.", "\"My degree in Chemical Engineering has prepared me in a few ways. My degree came with a heavy focus on petroleum which included safety issue reviews such as blowouts, fire, and other hazards. I also learned a great deal about hydrate formation and decomposition, H2S, toxic gases, and safe transportation and disposal of petroleum wastes. I graduated with a 3.6 GPA and was also president of the Student's Union, rounding out my time with some leadership experience.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my Mechanical Engineering degree, where I focused my time on Mechanical and Industrial engineering applications. My GPA was a 3.8, and I made the Deans List. My education has prepared me for a role with Company ABC in many ways including leadership, discipline and organizational skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Would you be willing to work over 40 hours a week?", "answers": ["Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on the interviewer's expectations. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask! \n\nConsider asking, 'What are the scheduling expectations for this position?' If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, 'Absolutely! No problem!' You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations. \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you CAN offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you. \n\nKeep in mind that, in most states, an employer cannot demand that an employee work more than 44 hours per week.", "\"I am available for full-time work which is preferably 8-5 Monday to Friday. I am happy to be a team player and work some overtime, as required. Will these hours meet your expectations?\"", "\"I am willing to work overtime as appropriate. How much and how often are the first questions that come to mind. I firmly believe that downtime, or personal time, is essential to recharging your batteries and staying focused, but I am certainly willing to be a team player.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Which is the leading publication or resource that you use for up-to-date news on the oil and gas sector?", "answers": ["It's crucial that you keep up-to-date on the latest news and changes within the oil industry. The industry is ever-changing, and you must be well-immersed to stay on top of your game. Luckily, there is a multitude of publications and resources available, to keep your knowledge current. It's a great idea to ask the interviewer if they have any suggestions for you to expand your knowledge base.", "\"I like to stick with a few of the most reliable resources for oil news such as Oil and Gas Journal, RigZone, and Oil & Gas 360. Before you stopped publishing, I also used to love to read The Lamp. Do you have any recommendations? I love to hear of new resources where I can learn.\"", "\"My favorite publication for up to date news is Oil and Gas Journal. I also look for trending tweets on Twitter, and I follow Exxon Mobil on social media, for up to date news. Do you have any additional resource recommendations? I'm always looking for new sources of reliable information about the industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Company ABC has a serious commitment to safety. How will you help us to uphold this commitment?", "answers": ["Safety is a vital topic in the oil and gas industry, and the interviewer would like to know that you are committed to helping Company ABC in their mission. Discuss the ways that you uphold safety standards in the workplace. Extra points if you can memorize the safety mission of Company ABC.", "\"I read online that Company ABC has a range of programs related to safety, and that your mission is, 'Safety above everything.' I will help you to uphold this commitment by delivering over and above expectations, completing my documentation fully and clearly, and by staying on top of industry trends and changes.\"", "\"When Company ABC says that the safety mission is to put safety above everything, it resonates with me. Values guide me and understand the importance of a healthy environment and a safe workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "With which industry-related computer programs are you most familiar?", "answers": ["The oil and gas industry has many options when it comes to computer programs, applications, and other software solutions. Speak briefly to the ones with which you're most comfortable. Also be sure to express that you can learn new applications and systems quickly.", "\"I have experience with several different computer software suites within the oil and gas industry - I've worked with NetSuite, Sage Business Cloud Enterprise Management, JD Edwards and Microsoft Dynamics most recently. I'm also comfortable with SAP Business. I also can easily learn new systems. Could you share with me which programs you use at Company ABC? I would be happy to gain a head start by taking online coursework and tutorials.\"", "\"I am newer to my career so I would say that I am entry-level in most oil and gas related programs. I am tech savvy, however, and can learn these systems quickly. I am advanced in MS Office Suite and have used CRM's in the past.\"", "\"I'm entry-level when it comes to most oil and gas programs. I'm quite familiar with Microsoft office,  I'm a fast learner, so I'm interested in any online tutorials or workshops that you have available for me.\"", "You sound confident and interested in learning, which is fantastic!"]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the Company ABC website and other online resources to ensure the queries you have are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers for from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working at Company ABC? \n- What is Company ABC's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\"", "\"A few questions come to mind, so thank you for asking. What's the next major project Company ABC is looking to tackle? I know you're seeking to expand this particular department, so I wonder what is next.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "You will often be working cross-departmentally. Tell me about a time you worked successfully with people outside of your department.", "answers": ["Collaboration and teamwork are significant topics in the oil and gas industry. There will be many opportunities for you to work alongside different people in varying roles, functions, and departments. The interviewer would like to know that you can work closely with others even when their job functions may not be exactly like yours. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a significant asset to Company ABC. \n\nMaybe you headed a project which required you to collaborate with the members of the engineering and HR teams. You may have had the opportunity to organize a volunteer activity or team building exercise, company-wide. Share any challenges that came up and what you learned from the experience.", "\"I have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. Primarily with the Engineering department and the HR department, arranging various contractors and agreements. Clear communication and clarity in expectations are of huge importance to me, and you can rest assured that I would work cohesively with any department.\"", "\"I bring experience in cross-functional teamwork in my current chemical engineering position. I believe that when expectations are communicated clearly from the beginning, a cross-functional team project can be very successful. I go into these types of projects with an understanding that everyone has their strengths and limitations based on their expertise and job function.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Do you think it is possible to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can be diplomatic in the workplace, even when you may not agree with your leader. Show the interviewer that it is possible for you to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader from time to time. Explain that you believe everyone is entitled to their own professional opinion, yet capable of maintaining respect for each other at the same time. Show that even if you disagree with the final decision they make, you support the direction the team is heading.", "\"What makes a great team member is not that they agree with everything but the level of respect and positive thought that goes into the person's communication style. It's okay to disagree; however, you have to communicate your thoughts professionally and ultimately comply with the leader's decision on a particular issue.\"", "\"I have had team members disagree with decisions that I have made as a manager, and it does not bother me unless they are disrespectful about the situation. I think it's great to face challenging thoughts in the workplace and I welcome varying trains of thought. In fact, I believe that sometimes disagreeing with the leader is the strongest sign of a good team member. If someone disagrees with me because they have the greater good of the team and/or the company in mind, then I want to hear that. And as a strong leader, I need to hear it.\"", "\"I feel that disagreements are very fundamental, and everybody is subject to there own opinions as long as the message is respectful and positive for the sake of the companies brand.\"", "Well thought out! It's great that you are not afraid to respectfully have an opinion of your own, allowing others to do the same."]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What is your personal mission statement?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you have a personal motto or mantra. Not everyone has a mission statement or personal mantra just off the cuff. In business, especially when entering leadership, this is an important question to ponder. Do you have a quote that inspires you or a saying that you grew up with that resonates with you?", "\"My mantra is that 'people who shine from within do not need the spotlight.' I feel that it is incredibly necessary to be a humble leader and I take this mission statement very seriously. I want my team to be in the spotlight rather than being the kind of leader that takes the credit for good work.\"", "\"My mission is to give my best 100% of the time. It's important to me that I have a great reputation in this industry through hard work and a positive attitude.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What have you done to improve your oil and gas knowledge in the last year?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are interested in your industry, and career growth, enough to take your professional development into your own hands. Even if your current employer does not offer perks like oil industry conferences or financial reimbursement for additional coursework, there is no reason why you cannot take the initiative. \n\nYou could: \n\n- Read industry or career-related books\n- Subscribe to relevant podcasts \n- Enhance your education with an additional certificate\n- Attend a conference related to your career or personal growth \n- Teach yourself a new software program\n- Read established journals and websites on a regular basis \n- Find a mentor who is senior to you, in your particular industry or career path", "\"It is important to me that I continue to grow as a professional oil and gas administrator. This year I took an Advanced Excel course so that I could take my competency from intermediate to expert. The course has helped me immensely, and I am currently looking into a leadership workshop as well.\"", "\"The oil and gas industry is always changing, and it's vital that I continue to gain knowledge, to keep up with the latest and greatest! I refer on a daily basis to a variety of energy-related journals and publications such as Oilweek, Midstream Business, and Gas & Oil magazine.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What is API gravity, and how is it calculated?", "answers": ["API gravity is American Institute Petroleum gravity. In short, it is a measure used to determine the weight of petroleum liquids compared to water. Here, the interviewer is not looking for you to give a math or physics lesson. They want to know that you are aware of basic terms and what they mean. Keep your response brief, and easy to follow.", "\"I understand there is a specific formula used to find the gravity of petroleum liquids from the specific gravity, also known as SG. The formula is: API gravity = 141.5/SG - 131.5. I also know that is the API gravity is 10+, it is classified as a light oil which will float on water. An API gravity under ten will sink and then becomes categorized as heavy oil.\"", "\"What I understand about API gravity is that it's a measurement that calculates the gravity of petroleum liquids compared to water. This calculation is how oil becomes classified from light, medium and heavy for example.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "How are crude oil prices determined?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you have a  understanding of pricing in the oil and gas industry. Although you are likely not an oil trader, you should still have a good idea of how pricing works when it comes to crude oil, gasoline, and more. Of course, supply and demand is a factor but try to dig a bit deeper when you respond.", "\"I understand that market conditions, as well as supply and demand, are critical factors when it comes to pricing crude oil. Other important factors include consumer habits, terrorist activities and other global threats, environmental issues, and also the grade of the crude itself.\"", "\"Crude oil prices are determined by multiple factors, which include market conditions, economic issues, environmental issues, and also the overall demand for the crude. The smallest market shift can alter the crude pricing, which is why some people dedicate their entire lives to learning about crude oil pricing and the factors that affect it.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Using the STAR method, tell me about the most significant problem you faced and solved.", "answers": ["Many interviewers like to apply the STAR method during discussions with their candidates. If you are not sure what STAR is: \n\n- Situation: talk about a challenge you have faced\n- Task: an overview of what you set out to achieve \n- Action: a brief on what you did, or how you assessed the situation\n- Result: the outcome of the steps that you took\n\nKeep your STAR example workplace related, and keep your response organized, helping you to avoid rambling.", "\"In my first year of working as an O&G administrator, I was asked to update and manage our Well Files into digital files. The job was daunting, so I broke the task alphabetically, and then by region. From there, I started to build the file database. The job took me about three months and, in the end, my manager was thrilled. The result was that the organized file system saved our department many hours of time when searching for oil-well specific data.\"", "\"My previous company had an alarmingly high accident rate. As a safety specialist, I was asked to evaluate multiple processes, assess the problem areas, and create a program to resolve the safety issues. I studied every accident, going back six years. Compiling the data, I then analyze my findings, to source out the weak spots. Knowing the weakest areas gave me a baseline from which to work. The entire project took me about four months. The result was, 18 months later, our safety rate went up 35%.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "This role requires extensive knowledge of pipeline systems and oil well machinery. How well do you understand this complicated equipment?", "answers": ["To fully understand pipeline systems and oil well machinery, you will need to have many years' experience in the industry. Briefly discuss with the interviewer how comfortable you are on these topics. Be sure to list any courses that you have taken on these topics.", "\"I have studied pipeline systems for some time now, and have worked in the oil industry for approximately eight years. There are always new things to learn, as the industry is ever-evolving; however, I would rate my knowledge at an intermediate to advanced level. If there is any coursework that you recommend I take before starting with Company ABC, I would be happy to comply.\"", "\"I am newer to the oil and gas industry; however, I have taken some coursework including fundamentals of offshore and onshore pipeline systems and am confidently in my knowledge base. I am currently working toward my Pipeline Operations Certificate which includes studies focused on corrosion theory, measurement fundamentals, and inspection techniques.\"", "\"I'm a tanker man, and we sometimes have to read the P&ID diagram so that we know where the pipeline on the barge leads to. I've also taken operation courses in school where we had to trace the pipeline of a simulated unit.\"", "These are solid examples of your exposure to complicated tasks. Good!"]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Documentation is crucial in this role. Rate your documentation abilities from 1-10 while supporting your answer.", "answers": ["Documentation, in the oil and gas industry, is crucial. When dealing with intense environmental situations, red tape and regulations, and the safety of employees and labor contractors, one must always ensure the I's are dotted, and the T's are crossed. Tell the interviewer that you understand the importance of clear and precise documentation. Give an example of what makes you great with documenting.", "\"I would rate my documentation skills as a 9/10. I am not perfect; however, I fully understand the potential repercussions related to unclear or messy paperwork and documentation. My current manager often compliments me on my reliable documentation, and I am sure she would be happy to comment when you call for an employment reference.\"", "\"I feel solid in my documentation skills, ensuring that my work remains organized and precise. Since what I do is closely related to safety initiatives, I am especially careful and pay close attention to detail. For that reason, I would rate my documentation skills as a 9.5/10.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Company ABC operates in many countries. Are you eligible to travel and work around the world?", "answers": ["Company ABC may operate in a multitude of regions and the interviewer would like to know that you can accommodate their potential needs as you grow within their organization. Be honest with your answer, but as open as possible. If you have limitations, be sure to discuss them. If you are free and able to travel, you can keep your response straightforward.", "\"I am eligible to travel and have no limitations when it comes to working around the world. My passport is valid, and I have a NEXUS border pass.\"", "\"Could you share with me more about the travel component in this role? I am eligible to travel and willing to, as needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Oil has different categories. Name a few.", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your overall knowledge when it comes to oil terminology. Here is an easy guide to different oil categories: \n\n1. Very light oils which include gasoline and jet fuels\n2. Light oils which include diesel, some fuel oils, and light crudes\n3. Medium oils, which include most crude oils \n4. Heavy oils such as heavy crude oils and some fuel oil \n\nShow the interviewer that you have an understanding of oil variances.", "\"I understand that there are many categories and types of oils. Many people believe that oil is all the same; however, it comes in ranges from heavy to very light oil. These types vary when it comes to viscosity and toxicity.\"", "\"I have studied all types of oil including very light, light, medium, and heavy. I have the broadest knowledge base with light oils and medium oils, including most crude oils.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What is OPEC, and why does it matter?", "answers": ["OPEC is the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries. It's an intergovernmental body with a mission to, 'coordinate and unify the petroleum policies of its member countries and ensure the stabilization of oil markets, in order to secure an efficient, economic and regular supply of petroleum to consumers, a steady income to producers, and a fair return on capital for those investing in the petroleum industry.'\n\nShow the interviewer that you have an understanding of OPEC and how it affects the way Company ABC does business.", "\"From my understanding, OPEC is a governing body that coordinates and unifies the petroleum policies of approximately 15 countries. OPEC decisions play an important role in the global oil market.\"", "\"I understand OPEC to be an intergovernmental body that helps regulate the global oil market and international regulations. Could you share with me how OPEC affects the way Company ABC does business?\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What is the most significant achievement you have on the horizon?", "answers": ["When you show that you have goals and achievements on the horizon, you are letting the interviewer know that you put thought into your career and what you bring to your employer. Employees who do not have goals set just beyond their reach are typically disengaged and unmotivated. This achievement does not need to be complicated. It can be as simple as finishing a beautiful Powerpoint presentation, finishing work-related coursework, or reaching a sales target.", "\"The most significant achievement on the horizon for me is the completion of my Advanced Excel and SAP courses. I have learned a great deal, and have a few modules to go. I look forward to applying these new skills to this role with Company ABC\"", "\"For the last two years, I have been working toward my master's degree in Chemical Engineering while also working full time. This effort has been challenging and rewarding all at the same time. My graduation date is this May, so that is the most significant achievement on the horizon.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Working in the oil and gas sector, you will often be expected to wear many different hats. The interviewer would like to know about a time when you were asked to take on a task for which you knew very little. Have you ever had to take on a responsibility or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. Include the outcome, and what you learned.", "\"My first management job was the scariest time in my career! I honestly didn't know if I was doing my job well. I led by instinct, took leadership workshops, and spent a lot of time reading books related to effective people management.\"", "\"I was once asked to train an employee on a new SAP system that I hardly knew. To prepare, I worked overtime, watching online tutorials so that the new employee's training time was well spent.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "When have you had to make a split second decision? How do you react under unexpected pressure?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how you handle pressure when an unexpected stressor arises. Being able to make quick decisions and think fast on your feet sets top-notch professionals out from the crowd. We all make a lot of choices every day, so start by telling the interviewer that you make a lot of quick decisions each day. Next, be prepared for a more significant example that will be sure to impress.", "\"In my current field admin role, this happens often! We handle a lot of contractor situations surrounding schedule and shift changes. Often, we have guidelines we follow, and there are also times when situations call for creative solutions. I make split-second decisions when resolving contractor matters, always keeping the best interests of the company in mind.\"", "\"My current position requires me to make tough decisions on a regular basis. I work well under pressure like that. With split-second decisions, I will always go with my initial instinct. Last week, I had two high-profile clients show up for a meeting at the same time. One client was late, and the other was early. I did not want anyone to feel bad for being late or too early, so I had each party placed in a different conference room. My colleague started the meeting with our early meeting while I met with the client who was late. It worked out well because I am no stranger to multi-tasking and I have great support staff.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you at this time in your career?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical 'I am looking for growth'response that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on Company ABC.", "\"I have been passively seeking a new position for quite some time and haven't jumped on anything yet because I want to make sure it's the right fit. I feel that this job is right for me, at this point in my career, because it offers an opportunity for me to utilize my new education in GIS while giving me an opportunity to advance in my management skills.\"", "\"I currently manage a small team of 12 field operators and engineers. Although I love the work, I am ready to stretch myself professionally into an organization with more production capacity, and teams of 25 or more. This year I dedicated myself to taking two leadership workshops, which I feel greatly prepared me to take on the challenge of the work volume present in Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "How would you describe your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Being a bright communicator, in written form, is an essential skill to master. Discuss any courses you have taken in communication, journalism, or writing.  If you have a sample of your written communication in the form of a report of a work-related article, you can certainly bring that example with you. Talk to the interviewer about your written communication abilities and support your answer with a case or story.\n\nHere are some words to describe your communication skills: \n\n- Articulate\n- Crisp\n- Eloquent \n- Formal\n- Informal \n- Punchy\n- Succinct", "\"My written communication skills are powerful. I often utilize written communications as a follow up to verbal communications. They provide a great resource for my FTE's and contractors to go back to, and reference, plus they might answer any questions that come up along the way.\"", "\"I have above average written communication skills. I am an experienced writer and have also written many successful quotes and RFP's in my career. I would describe my written communication skills as clear, concise, and thorough.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What type of work environment allows you to be the most productive?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how to ensure a healthy level of productivity from you. Are you able to be productive in any environment or are there particular types of situations that you find distracting? Discuss your preferences with the interviewer. Be sure to research the kind of environment that offered at Company ABC before the interview.", "\"I understand that your work environment is very collaborative. I come from a similar environment and have found that I can be very productive when there is the 'buzz' of a team around me. I can also be productive in quieter environments although that isn't my preference.\"", "\"I work well in a high pressure, demanding environment that requires me to work smart and make my mark. I am competitive and love a significant challenge. How would you best describe the work environment at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Tell me how you brought value to your most recent position.", "answers": ["This question offers another way for the interviewer to ask about your recent successes and bragging points. The interviewer wants to know which top skills you will highlight if you had to narrow down where you brought the most value. \n\nPerhaps you influenced changes that saved the company money. Maybe you were the top performing manager in your department. Think of your strengths in action! If you are reliable, talk about how consistent your work has been and how you are in constant support of your coworkers. If you have a strong work ethic, share how you accomplished a project in the midst of harsh obstacles.", "\"In my last position, I brought value through delivering an increased customer base and a stronger contractor network.  My ability to build strong relationships helped me secure and maintain a great deal of new business.\"", "\"My organizational skills made an incredible impact on my current company. Upon my arrival, I quickly implemented new filing systems for both physical and digital files. I also introduced the use of Trello, a project management app that we now use office-wide.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "When given an important assignment, how do you approach handling it?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you first approach a critical assignment. Are you the individual who will take an assignment head-on, or do you need to research and plan early? Do you jump in and get it all done immediately or do you balance it with other assignments? Talk to the interviewer about how you approach essential tasks at work.", "\"When my supervisor gives me an important assignment or task I am sure to assess the depth of the project, then take a look at my schedule to see how I can appropriately balance it with my other work. I do not procrastinate because then it's easy to get behind.\"", "\"I lay out all the deadlines, figure out the deliverables, priority order, and then do all the research needed to make informed decisions. I keep a written \"to-do\" list and transfer project deadlines into my calendar to stay on task.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "When have you shown great integrity at work?", "answers": ["The oil and gas industry has not always enjoyed a reputation of honesty, transparency, and integrity. Times have changed over the decades; however, and Company ABC needs to know that you are someone driven my integrity in the workplace. Integrity is best displayed through honesty and consistent moral values. Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you show your integrity in the workplace.", "\"Honesty and integrity are two values at the center of my being. I like to think I practice this in the workplace by always doing the right thing by the company, its customers, and its people. In my current role, I have led my team in turning down business from companies that we don't believe share our value of integrity.\"", "\"Integrity is fundamental to me. I was once given credit for a report that I did not create. I did present the report, but one of my staff members had put it together for me. I made sure to show thanks for the compliment and alert everyone to its creator. I took my subordinate out to lunch later for making me look good.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "What is the difference between a leader and a manager?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you understand what makes a leader genuinely stand out. Just because you are a manager, that does not mean you are a leader.\n\nA real leader is someone who makes others want to jump on board with their mission and follow them. A manager is just someone who has people under them. To be an excellent leader, you should offer a balance between the two. You need to be able to have people buy into your vision but at the same time, show authority when necessary.", "\"A manager is someone who has a team of people who answer to them. That person simply has the responsibility of 'managing' the team's work. A leader, on the other hand, is someone of influence and, I believe, anyone can be a leader - no matter their job title or position.\"", "\"To me, leadership is a mindset versus a title. A manager is more of a job title. Anyone can possess leadership skills, but a great manager will have leadership skills along with the ability to direct his or her team to success.\""]}, {"topic": "Oil+and+Gas", "question": "Is compensation the most important factor for you when taking a new job?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how much emphasis you put on pay when considering a new position. In addition to compensation, there are many other factors to a fulfilling career. These other factors may include:\n\n- work/life balance\n- amount of travel involved in the role\n- overall medical and health benefits\n- additional perks such as car allowance, cell allowance, spending account\n- the industry you will be working in\n- amount of vacation time\n- the type of clients you would be working with\n- the location of the company\n- career growth opportunity\n- the size of your new team\n- the company's reputation\n- overall workplace culture. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about other factors that are important to you when considering a new job. If you are not sure on details for this role, you can ask!", "\"Salary is important to me because I know that I am skilled and well educated. With that said, I do look at the full picture before accepting a position, which includes factors such as benefits, the amount of paid vacation time, the type of work challenges and opportunities and work/life balance.\"", "\"Several factors are important to me when taking a job. Compensation is a driving component but so is the company mission, culture, benefits, and location. Right now, I am looking to have an easier commute than I currently experience, and I'm also looking to join an industry leading organization where I know I can learn, grow and develop as a professional.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "When do you best demonstrate yourself as a leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are confident about your leadership abilities and that you understand when your leadership abilities have been most useful.\n\nPerhaps you best demonstrate yourself as a leader when your manager is away. Maybe you often jump into a leadership mindset when a co-worker is struggling. Think about a recent time when an employee on your team was successful at something because of your leadership skills. Discuss the scenario and how your leadership skills made the difference.", "\"I best demonstrate myself as a leader when I know that a coworker could use my assistance. I seem to be a natural teacher and mentor which means that when someone is struggling, my first instinct is to train them. Just recently, I coached a new employee on a sales technique that helped her to achieve her quota for the first time. I look forward to working in this role with you because it will allow me to take on further leadership opportunities.\"", "\"In my current position, every time my current manager is away, I take on the role of leader for our team. This situation usually occurs one day per week. When you call him for a reference, he will be able to tell you that I have naturally stepped into the responsibilities associated with being a leader.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "If we hire you at Company ABC, how will you make an impact in the first 90 days?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you already have a plan of action in place for your success with Company ABC, should you be the chosen candidate. Show your initiative by preparing a 90-day success plan. If you are applying for a sales position, discuss how you plan to resuscitate dormant accounts, for example. \n\nBe sure to address the needs that the company has outlined in the job posting or job description. For instance, if the job description mentions a \"must-have\" of strong communication skills, be sure to comment on how you plan to utilize your exceptional communication skills to see success in a short amount of time.", "\"In my first 90 days with Company ABC, I would like to make an impact by excelling in my training and learning all that I can about the processes here. I want to develop strong relationships with my new coworkers and customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "\"Assuming that the projects have different stakeholders, I interview each to determine the value of increased productivity, morale or revenue, decreased costs, and the overall impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "The utilities industry is highly regulated. How do you stay on top of policy changes and trends related to our business?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have a keen and sincere interest in the utility industry. Show that you see this as more than 'just a job.' Talk to the interviewer about a couple of ways that you stay in touch regarding industry trends and policy changes. It's also a great idea to ask the interviewer about their favorite industry resources. This question can start an informative conversation and potentially give you new resources for industry based knowledge.", "\"My go-to resources for industry related news would be utilitydive.com as well as waterworld.com. I prefer these resources because I can subscribe to daily inbox updates as well as their monthly newsletter. Their sources are strong, and the content is always fresh. What are your favorite resources for industry trends and related news?\"", "\"It is tough to keep up on the ever-changing policies in this industry. I have set up google alerts for particular keywords. Also, I meet with a mentor once a month who had a long-time career in the utility industry. During our meetings, we discuss the industry in great detail. I look forward to these meetings because I learn so much!\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Describe your leadership skills.", "answers": ["If the position you are interviewing for requires leadership skills, you need to come prepared with examples of when you have been an active leader. \n\nIf this is an entry-level role without a leadership component, the interviewer wants to see that you can take the initiative when there is an opportunity. What type of keywords best describe your leadership style?", "\"In previous employer reviews I have had my leadership style described as attentive, open, and confident. I will always listen to my team and give them the benefit of the doubt when it comes to their performance. An example of this would be with my current sales team. When one of my team members is not hitting their quota, that is when I will step in and begin coaching. I want to believe they know their job unless they show me otherwise. This type of leadership has worked well with my team, and we are the #1 sales team in our region.\"", "\"I have taken many workshops and courses to improve my leadership skills over the years. My leadership qualities are best summed as dedicated, attentive, and motivating. I like to recognize my employees' small wins because that motivates them to continue achieving.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I have been cautious when paving my career path. Things have gone very well for me so far, and I am thankful for that. This position with Company ABC will be a perfect compliment to both my short and long-term career plan.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike, that works too! Merely share that you have the means to get to work consistently and on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. I have a well-maintained vehicle, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to your office every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Would you be willing to work over 40 hours a week?", "answers": ["Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on expectations. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask! \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you can offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you.", "\"I am available for full-time work which is preferably 8-5 Monday to Friday. I am happy to be a team player and work some overtime, as required. Will these hours be enough to meet your expectations?\"", "Consider asking, \"What are the scheduling expectations for this position?\" If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, \"Absolutely! No problem!\" You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations."]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you receive motivation on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of competition for me.\"", "Here are some ways that an employer may try to motivate you. Which ones resonate most with you? \n\n- Incentive programs where points are earned\n- Showing complete trust in your work and performance\n- Setting smaller, more achievable goals\n- Helping you to find your greater career purpose\n- Being a positive example to you \n- Maintaining an open and transparent workplace\n- Personalized incentives vs. Team driven incentives \n- Getting to know you on a personal level\n- Positive feedback based rewards system\n- Offering a stable work/life balance by encouraging time off\n- Letting you know your voice matters\n- Allowing you to take the lead on projects that excite you \n- Handing out big-picture projects, so you feel that you are contributing to the company's future\n- Public recognition"]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "At Company ABC we believe in continued education opportunities. What course or workshop would you take, if given the opportunity?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have a keen interest in gaining new skills by continuing your education when the opportunity arises. \n\nTell the interviewer about any course that you would like to take, but be sure to keep your answer industry related. You should avoid saying that you want to attend a class on dog grooming if you are interviewing for a career in the utility industry. \n\nIt's also a great idea to ask the interviewer if, after reviewing your resume, they would suggest a particular course to fill any potential gaps in your skill set.", "\"I agree that continued education is essential. If given the opportunity to take any coursework, I would like to complete my Project Manager certificate. Being PM certified would help me to manage the aspects of our commercial utility projects more efficiently. Do you have a recommendation for any courses I could be taking to strengthen my skill set?\"", "\"That is a great question, and I appreciate that you consider continued education options for your employees. If I could take any related coursework, I would choose to learn more about the future of electric utilities and organizational behavior. Are there any particular courses you recommend that I take?\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Company ABC has many different departments and growth opportunities. Where would you like to see your career go with us in the next couple of years?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know that you think about the future and are actively working towards your career goals. Better yet, they want to know how working for them will help you to accomplish those goals! Take a look at the job postings available with Company ABC. Perhaps there is a particular location or department to which you would like to transition. Talk to the interviewer about the ways you could see your career flourishing with Company ABC.", "\"I noticed that Company ABC has opportunities for management and new employee training. My goal would be to become a corporate trainer with Company ABC because I know the industry well and have been told that I am a talented mentor and teacher. I believe there are many great opportunities for my career to flourish with Company ABC and I look forward to spending many years with your company.\"", "\"I have some pretty lofty career aspirations, and after researching your organization and learning more about this position, I feel that this role fits with my future aspirations. I would love to see myself promoted based on my hard work and results, eventually managing my team.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Would you say you are a better verbal or written communicator?", "answers": ["In which manner do you prefer to communicate - written or verbal? Discuss your preference with the interviewer and support your answer.", "\"I prefer verbal communication because I feel that with written communication, miscommunication can happen due to lack of tone, fluctuation, expression and body language. I will always choose a face to face conversation whenever possible.\"", "\"I like to leverage both methods of communications when dealing in business. Sometimes, situations call for verbal communications and other times, written.  As a rule of thumb, I tend to practice verbal communications, with written follow up or vice versa. Utilizing multiple methods creates repetition and therefore, change.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Interviewing, hiring and onboarding are expensive and time-consuming tasks for a company. Assure the interviewer that you have a specific interest in working for Company ABC. Come prepared with examples of why Company ABC is your top choice. This example could include commenting on individual industry awards and accolades that Company ABC has achieved in the past. Perhaps they are well known for their community outreach efforts or their strong workplace culture. Make your answer engaging and genuine.", "\"It's important to me that I work for a socially responsible organization. I like that Company ABC has implemented a new water conservation program as well as the fact that you donate many dollars and volunteer hours to local charities. You are a company with heart, and I put a great deal of value on that.\"", "\"The primary reasons your company stands out to me include your focus on employee development and continued education. You have a strong reputation for nurturing the human resources that you have. I would be so grateful to work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Have you personally used the services of Company ABC? If so, what was your overall experience?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you have had the pleasure of experiencing the products/services of Company ABC first hand. You should always have some personal experience with the company before going to your first interview. If you are not a customer of Company ABC then perhaps you could call their office to inquire about their utility services. This way, you can comment on the customer service that you received. Big or small, be prepared to say YES - you have experienced Company ABC first hand.", "\"I have been a customer of Company ABC for three years now. My experience has been a positive one. I specifically recall last year when my invoice was incorrect. I called the customer service line, and the representative was helpful and friendly. I have recommended Company ABC to my friends and family in the past.\"", "\"I have not been a direct customer of Company ABC; however, I did call into your customer service department a couple of weeks ago to discuss the possibility of changing my services over to you. Unfortunately, I am on a contract with one of your competitors until the end of November. My experience with Company ABC was great so I will be switching over to you as soon as I am able.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Our industry is highly competitive. In your opinion, what are we doing right at Company ABC? What could we be doing better?", "answers": ["Although the interviewer would like to know what they could be doing better, this is indeed not an invitation to do a deep dive into the things you do not like about Company ABC. Keep your answer firmly focused on what Company ABC is doing right. Offer a lighthearted suggestion for improvement. This suggestion could be mentioning a small change in their online job portal, or perhaps a stronger social media presence. Be sure to complete your answer on a positive note by complimenting Company ABC and affirming that you want to work for them.", "\"I understand that this industry is very competitive; however, I have always seen Company ABC as the industry leader. I enjoy how you relate to your customers through your marketing and branding efforts. It's all very relate-able content. If I could make one suggestion, I would comment on the user interface for your online job portal. I noticed that it isn't mobile friendly. With 67% of job seekers being mobile users, you would likely see a strong increase in applicants by making your job portal mobile friendly. Other than that, I like what I have experienced so far. I'm excited to have the opportunity to work at Company ABC!\"", "\"Company ABC is doing so many things right, which is why I am so excited to be meeting with you today! I like the fact that your employees are so happy to work here. Your online reviews are solid. If I could make a suggestion, I would recommend a more robust website as so many customers are on mobile.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "What are your greatest strengths? How will these skills benefit Company ABC, if hired?", "answers": ["Reviewing the job description and the company website will give you some direction on which qualities Company ABC values most. Share your most valuable strengths. You can refer to the list of responsibilities within the job description to gain a better understanding of what strengths Company ABC will value most from you. \n\nExplain how your strengths will help you to accomplish the job-related tasks and, better yet, help you to exceed company expectations. Try to offer unique advantages that will set you apart from other candidates. Avoid generic terms.", "\"I have exceptional loyalty when it comes to my clients and employer. I am also quick to solve problems, which helps me handle customer issues with ease. These strengths will help me to build exceptional relationships and maintain customer satisfaction.\"", "Some great strengths to mention are: \n\n- Communicative\n- Loyal\n- Collaborative \n- Tech Savvy\n- Flexible in Schedule/Availability \n- Persistent and Determined\n- Eager for Knowledge/New Skills"]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Why do you want to pursue a career opportunity in the utilities industry?", "answers": ["Company ABC is looking for motivated individuals who want to grow with them. Before your interview, take some time to think through your career goals. Share your career plans with the interviewer, while remaining focused on the utility industry. \n\nThe last thing the interviewer wants to hear is that you want to become a police officer but the utility industry pays too much for you to walk away quite yet. Talk about how this position will help you achieve industry-related career goals.", "\"I am passionate about the utility industry because these are essential services for any well-developed community. The utility industry allows me to tap into multiple career paths if desired. The diversity it offers is significant and exciting.\"", "\"My formal education and previous work history are related to the utility industry. I am excited to be considered for this position so that I can further grow my experience in this industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Tell me about the most important skill you have gained in the past year. How will that skill help you succeed in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you continue to better yourself by gaining new skills and strengthening your existing skills. Discuss what you believe to be the most valuable skill acquired in the past year. Explain to the interviewer that you are excited for the opportunity to grow yourself, professionally.", "\"I think it is imperative to introduce new skills to my repertoire continually. This year, I am most excited about the coding knowledge I have gained. This knowledge has helped me to expand my abilities in more areas than I initially expected, and I hope to utilize my coding skills in this position with Company ABC.\"", "Here is a list of transferable skills that you may have gained in your most recent work history: \n\n- Writing new procedures \n- Ability to quickly take and understand instruction \n- Professional written communication \n- Learning a new industry or trade\n- Public speaking or presenting \n- Delegating tasks \n- Hiring, terminating, and on-boarding"]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Sometimes our customers do not understand their bill and they will reach us with questions. Tell me about your communication skills and how you would respond to an irate customer.", "answers": ["Keeping a customer calm when they do not understand their bill can be a challenging task. The interviewer wants to hear about a situation where you used your customer service skills to handle an irate customer. Highlight your ability to maintain a relaxed demeanor, and your ability to empathize with the customer, while coming to a smart solution that works for both parties.", "\"I had a customer call last week because her bill was twice the amount of what she was expecting. She was distraught because her bill has always consistently been the same. I listened and let her know I understood where she was coming from, ensuring her I would move as quickly as I could to find a solution. Listening and empathizing helped her to calm down and ease the tension during the call. My manager agreed that we would, one time only, discount her bill by half. She was happy, and we kept a customer complaint from blowing out of proportion.\"", "\"Irate customers are usually just wishing to be heard. If I am to come across a customer who is unhappy, I would ask them to tell me more about what was bothering them. Once I have a clear understanding of the true problem, I can then ask the customer to tell me what a viable solution would be for them.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you can do more than the bare minimum. Show that you can react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her workload so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help but also benefited me by way of organization.\"", "\"I often go above and beyond when it comes to helping new employees to feel comfortable and welcomed. In my current position, I like to take them under my wing and show them the ropes in our organization, and industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Looking at your resume, it seems there are certain skills necessary for this position that do not stand out. How do you think you will be able to compensate for these missing skills?", "answers": ["Most job descriptions will have a long list of requirements. Hiring managers are aware that, to find a candidate that checks ALL of the boxes, can sometimes be impossible. Do not fret if you are missing some of the \"nice to have\" or even a couple of \"must have\" skills listed in the job description. Be open about your shortcomings and discuss with the interviewer how you plan to compensate for those.", "\"Could you share with me which specific skills you feel are not standing out? I would be happy to give any clarification on those skills. If there are gaps that need filling, I am very willing to take additional coursework or training.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "How do you manage a large workload?", "answers": ["Start your answer by clarifying with the interviewer that you never let a large workload stress you out. For instance, you can tell that interviewer that, each morning, you review your tasks using a task manager application. (If you do not have one, just Google search 'task manager application' and giving one a try). Discuss how you complete each task by priority level. Before you know it, your large workload is complete!", "\"When I have a large workload, I do not stress over the tasks that are in front of me. Rather, I make a simple plan of which tasks are a high priority and which tasks are a low priority. The higher priority tasks, I complete first. Through this system, I can focus on my tasks individually, rather than stress out by the multitude of tasks ahead of me.\"", "\"When I have a large workload on my plate, I do not stress over the tasks that are in front of me. Rather, I make a simple plan of which tasks are a high priority and which tasks are a low priority. The higher priority tasks, I complete first. Through this system, I can focus on my tasks individually, rather than stress out by the multitude of tasks ahead of me.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get more comfortable. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "On a scale from 1 to 10, how honest are you?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you are a sincere person or do you have room for growth? This question could be a tricky question as nobody is always 100% honest. Answer to the best of your ability and back your reply by speaking about your ethics.", "\"I would love to give myself a 10/10 for honesty but truthfully - nobody is 100% honest all of the time. I will give myself an nine because I always do my best to be as honest as possible.\"", "\"I put a heavy focus on honesty and trustworthiness in the workplace, as well as in my personal life.  Because I strive for complete honesty, I will rate myself as a 10/10. My values are solid.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "How do you respond to feedback?", "answers": ["Receiving feedback from a manager or supervisor can be tough. You can't always predict what they may say, and you also can't always predict how you might feel in response. Learning how to respond when given a performance review or negative feedback is essential.", "\"Even though it can be difficult to hear criticism, I always pause before I respond and take time to think about it first. If it's something that catches me by surprise, I usually ask for clarification. I want to grow and improve. The more specific my supervisor can be in their feedback, the more helpful it is.\"", "\"I have worked hard on learning to graciously accept all forms of feedback, even when it comes unsolicited. I feel that I can accept feedback very well and, in the process of growing, I have also taught myself how to give great feedback to my team.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to tell the interviewer a few things about yourself. You can begin with your recent education, volunteer work, or talk about your travels. Bring up anything that is interesting and highlights your ability to be a responsible, reliable, and bright individual.", "\"A bit about me - I love to travel, read, and conduct research. I am a recent grad from Columbia University and have spent the past 12 months traveling the world. It was the best experience that I could have given myself as I was able to learn so much from seeing how the rest of the world lives. I returned to the US just last month and have been actively looking for work the past couple of weeks. I am looking forward to getting into the routine of a career again.\"", "\"With pleasure! I have over ten years of experience in the utility industry and am interested in growing my career to the next level. On a more personal note, I love to read, go hiking and spend a lot of my extra time volunteering with the humane society.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "What would you do if a client asked you about a product or service and you were unsure of the answer?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you are an independent thinker. Explain that you would take the time to try and figure out the answer, but you are not afraid to ask questions if you need to.", "\"If I had a client ask me about something that I didn't know enough about, I would find the answer for them before giving a potentially false answer. I am okay with admitting when I don't know something, and I love to learn new things. Of course, I would find the answer quickly by asking the appropriate person or finding it within the company's internal resources.\"", "\"I am accustomed to having to think on my feet and come up with a creative answer based on the information I have at hand. With that said, I'm not going to tell a client something that is untrue or could potentially create a long-term issue. I'm not afraid of putting myself in a position where I don't know everything or am not the expert. I am happy to get out of my comfort zone to grow, learn, and help a customer. I will not hesitate to involve the appropriate parties, do my research, and work collaboratively to solve the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Utilities", "question": "What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the biggest change in this industry over the past 3 years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}]